<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-08-02T17:23:21+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why this website?</title><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why this website?"/><published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/"><![CDATA[<p style="margin-bottom:0.5cm;"></p> <h3 id="early-years"><b>Early years</b></h3> <p>For a long time, I have wanted to deploy my own website. I used to spend summer days exploring how HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and other programming languages and tools could be used to develop the front-end of a web-browser page. However, I did not have the skill at the time to make that vision a reality.</p> <div class="row"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/website-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/website-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/website-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/website.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" title="Code of a website" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Snippet of website development code </div> <p>Now that I have had some experience with programming, and looking for the right tools and resources, I came up with a solution that enables me to make my past child goal a dream come true. But what could I show the world in my website? Will it just be a random access point which will serve no purpose?</p> <p>Well, another thing which I always envisioned (but admit to being lazy on putting hands on) was to compile all the information and expertise I have gathered over time in a single place. I would then be able to access this information wherever I wanted to and show it to the right people at the right time.</p> <p style="margin-bottom:1cm;">The combination of these two goals merged into a single one, which stands to be the website from which you are now reading in this post. And now that I have mentioned the word 'post', here comes the third purpose for the website that surged as I was exploring what functionalities I could give it: sharing my ideas and experiences.</p> <h3 id="what-to-post"><b>What to post?</b></h3> <p>Since social media is out of question at this point, what kind of posts will I be doing in here? Instead of quick ‘stories’ with pictures and videos from what is happening at the moment (which I find a little privacy obstructive), I will be doing more insightful posts. In the first days of the website, there will be more posts about some work and projects I have laid my hands on. But it will not stay that way for long. As I have mentioned, I want to document what is possible when it comes to my past involvements in projects. Once that stage is over, it will be a mix between this and adventures, experiences, ideas, and goals for the future.</p> <p>For the professional related content, there will be more technical stuff, but I will also try to give a simpler view into what is going on. This way, more people may get to know more about my work and in turn it is self proof that I understand the concepts at a great level:</p> <blockquote> <p>If you can’t explain it to a six-year-old, you don’t understand it yourself. - <a href="https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/35209/which-of-these-quotes-are-actually-einsteins-if-any">Einstein probably</a></p> </blockquote> <p style="margin-bottom:1cm;"></p> <p><em>Lourenço</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="website"/><category term="guidance"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Background & motives]]></summary></entry></feed>