<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-06-21T20:03:00+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">First time for everything</title><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First time for everything"/><published>2024-06-13T23:39:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-13T23:39:00+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/"><![CDATA[<p>Here I am testing the blog feature of the website. Or at least that’s the way I call it. It seems to be more something towards a ‘post with detail’ kind of thing and not so much for quick writing and notes. I guess my experience with blogs is non existent so maybe that’s what a blog really is. Perhaps there is a multitude of blog types out there. And I’m going to create my own.</p> <p>First and foremost, I can say that I am still quite a newbie when it comes to text formatting. Unless we are talking about LaTeX, which, from what I have been exploring, is somewhat supported in this website environment.</p> \[\begin{equation*} E = mc^2 \end{equation*}\] <p>And there we go. I just Einsteined out of this!</p> <p>So… what is going to be the purpose of this blog? I guess I’ll be sharing my work and life experiences. To whom? Well, if you are reading this, you are one of the people. But there is no general audience in particular. I am the audience and those who end up here are just curious minds who perhaps are willing to know more about me. By exposing my ideas and objectives in a public manner but without their direct knowledge sounds exciting. Not commiting to the goals I am setting but knowing that someone might be aware of my lazyness or disregard for achieving more might make me more productive. An RSS feed system can be implemented in the website and, if people were to use it, than stakes would feel certainly higher.</p> <p>So let’s break down some objectives here for the next few days. Hell, let’s be more objective. Let’s set objectives for <strong>tomorrow</strong>:</p> <ul> <li>Pull day (Gym)</li> <li>Do 2 exams for <em>Flight testing</em> course and the remaining exercises of the last exam I was doing</li> <li>Review exercises I have already done for <em>Distributed Predictive Control and Estimation</em></li> <li>Keep developing the website</li> <li>Make a blog post!</li> </ul> <p>Just generic objectives. In the future, I want to separate work from personal life and everything else. I need to be careful with what I have written in here. Privacy is something I have always valued a lot and I don’t wish to change in that manner. I am exposing my mind for good reasons, not to reduce my privacy. Let’s keep it simple for now. Post done. Heading out.</p> <p><em>Lourenço Gouveia Faria</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="testing"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The very first post of the blog]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>