<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-06-22T21:38:55+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why this website?</title><link href="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why this website?"/><published>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://louxonline.github.io/blog/2024/first-post/"><![CDATA[<h3>Early years</h3> <p>For a long time, I have wanted to deploy my own website. I used to spend a few summer days exploring how HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and other programming languages and tools could be used to develop the front-end of a web-browser page. However, I did not have the skill at the time to make that vision a reality.</p> <p>Now that I have had some experience with programming, and looking for the right tools and resources, I came up with a solution that enables me to make my past child goal a dream come true. But what could I show the world in my website? Will it just be a random access point which will serve no purpose?</p> <p>Well, another thing which I always envisioned (but admit to being lazy on putting hands on) was to compile all the information and expertise I have gathered over time in a single place. I would then be able to access this information wherever I wanted to and show it to the right people at the right time if time arises.</p> <p>The combination of these two goals merged into a single one, which stands to be the website from which you are now reading in this post. And now that I have mentioned the word 'post', here comes the third purpose for the website that surged as I was exploring what functionalities I could give it: sharing my ideas and experiences. You may be asking yourself: <i>Couldn't you do the same thing in a usual social media platform?</i> The answer to that question is <b>yes</b>, I could definitely do that. However, I believe that it would not be the same thing.</p> <h3>The problem with social media</h3> <p>Whenever I check on a social media platform, people tend to show the good moments, achievements, and everything positive that there is to share from their own lives. I hope you know that life is not all about that, unfortunately. But being exposed to everyone’s ‘perfect’ lives would sometimes kind of drive me nuts, and I deliberately started using social media less and less, becoming a passive user in the virtual world where everyone was getting updates from one another. That’s bad right? After some thorough thinking, I concluded: <b>No</b>, maybe it is not that bad.</p> <p>I began to think about how things worked before the internet even existed. How did people get to know what was happening in their friends and families lives? The obvious answer was: by spending time together and talking it through. What about celebrities and public figures? Perhaps that has not changed so much. The updates would come from general media outlets and the television. With the internet and after the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot-com_bubble">Dot-com bubble</a>, we got social media platforms, and suddenly everyone was living like a celebrity. Getting the same treatment as one, with different means, perhaps a smaller outreach, but getting their lives watched by countless others. And everyone seemed to enjoy it.</p> <p>I reached the point where I thought to myself that I have had enough of that, eventually transitioned from passive user to no user at all. Was it a good choice? Actually, I feel like it was, and there was a mixed reaction from those who knew me. Some said I was in the wrong, isolating myself from everyone else, and others seemed more interested in knowing what was going on in my life since I was now neither sharing it nor communicating virtually nothing whenever something would come up. The old way was now the way to get things up to date. I reckon that there must be a balance between online sharing and no online presence at all. Times have changed, and simply saying that the old school way is completely and utterly acceptable in any given situation is not a realistic approach.</p> <h3>What to post?</h3> <p>Since social media is out of question at this point, what kind of posts will I be doing in here? Instead of quick ‘stories’ with pictures and videos from what is happening at the moment (which I find a little privacy obstructive), I will be doing more insightful posts. In the first days of the website, there will be more posts about some work and projects I have laid my hands on. But it will not stay that way for long. As I have mentioned, I want to document what is possible when it comes to my past involvements in projects. Once that stage is over, it will be a mix between this and adventures, experiences, ideas, and goals for the future.</p> <p>For the professional related content, there will be more technical stuff, but I will also try to give a simpler view into what is going on. This way, more people may get to know more about my work and in turn it is self proof that I understand the concepts at a great level:</p> <blockquote> <p>If you can’t explain it to a six-year-old, you don’t understand it yourself. - <a href="https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/35209/which-of-these-quotes-are-actually-einsteins-if-any">Einstein probably</a></p> </blockquote> <p><em>Lourenço</em></p> <p><small><ins>Edited:</ins> June 22, 2024</small></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="website"/><category term="guidance"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Reasons & navigation tips]]></summary></entry></feed>